<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright 2024 Synfig contributors -->
<component type="desktop-application">
  <id>org.synfig.SynfigStudio</id>
  <launchable type="desktop-id">org.synfig.SynfigStudio.desktop</launchable>
  <name>Synfig Studio</name>
  <summary>Create and edit 2D animations and compositions</summary>
  <description>
    <p>Synfig Studio is a free and open-source 2D animation software, designed as powerful industrial-strength solution for creating film-quality animation using a vector and bitmap artwork. It eliminates the need to create animation frame-by frame, allowing you to produce 2D animation of a higher quality with fewer people and resources.</p>

    <p>Features:</p>
    <ul>
      <li>Can manipulate vector and bitmap artwork</li>
      <li>Automatic tweening (independent from FPS)</li>
      <li>Multitude of layers of various types (geometry primitives, shapes, gradients, fratals)</li>
      <li>Full-featured bone system</li>
      <li>Filters and effects for compositing (blurs, distortions, color manipulation, masks)</li>
      <li>All color operations use High Dynamic-Range Imaging (HDRI)</li>
      <li>Pentablet-friendly tools</li>
      <li>Sound support</li>
      <li>Linking data on file or parameter-level</li>
      <li>Automatic animation using mathematical functions</li>
    </ul>
  </description>

  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default" environment="gnome">
      <caption>Synfig Studio main window</caption>
      <image type="source">https://i0.wp.com/www.synfig.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/screenshot-07.png</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot environment="gnome">
      <caption>Synfig Studio main window</caption>
      <image type="source">https://i0.wp.com/www.synfig.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/screenshot-1.png</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot environment="gnome">
      <caption>Synfig Studio main window</caption>
      <image type="source">https://i0.wp.com/www.synfig.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/screenshot-10.png</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot environment="gnome">
      <caption>Synfig Studio main window</caption>
      <image type="source">https://i0.wp.com/www.synfig.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/screenshot-11.png</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot environment="gnome:dark">
      <caption>Synfig Studio main window</caption>
      <image type="source">https://i0.wp.com/www.synfig.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/screenshot-14.png</image>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>

  <releases>
    <release version="1.5.4" date="2025-01-18">
      <url type="details">https://github.com/synfig/synfig/blob/v1.5.4/ChangeLog-development.md</url>
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>Feature Enhancements: Several new capabilities have been introduced, such as an angle converter that supports integers, hotkeys for locking/unlocking past and future keyframes, a new 'Alpha Intersection' blending mode, and enhanced palette clipboard functionality. Additionally, initial support for SVG Text elements and Lottie Text Layers has been added.</li>
          <li>Stability and Quality Improvements: Numerous bug fixes address critical issues including rendering artifacts in outlines, undefined behavior during undo/redo operations after value conversion, crashes related to malformed PNG imports or null devices, and various UI/UX inconsistencies. Specific fixes include improved SVG importer behavior, corrected bline tool interactions, and resolution of font rendering issues.</li>
          <li>Performance and Code Refinements: Significant refactoring efforts have been undertaken, including the porting of several layers (Bevel, Noise gradient, HalfTone2 &amp; 3) to the more efficient Cobra rendering engine. Other improvements include optimizing code for image sequence import, enhancing parameter passing by reference, and general code style cleanups.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.5.3" date="2024-08-23">
      <url type="details">https://github.com/synfig/synfig/blob/v1.5.3/ChangeLog-development.md</url>
      <description>
        <p>Synfig Studio version 1.5.3 delivers new features and important bugfixes for all platforms.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.4.5" date="2024-06-25">
      <url type="details">https://synfig.readthedocs.io/en/latest/releases/stable/1.4.5.html</url>
      <description>
        <p>Synfig Studio version 1.4.5 delivers some important bugfixes for all platforms.</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Fixed line end distortions when using the drawing tool</li>
          <li>Fixed an error that prevented importing images into an unsaved SIF file that had not yet been saved</li>
          <li>Fixed an error that caused the program to crash when trying to move an object that is attached to a curve, if that curve is exported</li>
          <li>Fixed an error when closing the program that occurred if bones were used in the active document</li>
          <li>Fixed an error that caused the program to crash when creating curves consisting of two points that are too close to each other</li>
          <li>Fixed a program crash when using a graphics tablet in Linux on the Wayland graphics system</li>
          <li>Fixed a program crash when clicking on rows in the Library Panel</li>
          <li>The "Open With History" button in the file open dialog is now only active when a file with the extension "sfg" is selected</li>
          <li>Fixed a the GUI crash when clicking on a control point with the Graphs panel active</li>
          <li>Pixel information about the current cursor position is now only requested if the Info panel is active</li>
          <li>Fixed memory leak when importing PNG files</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
  </releases>

  <url type="homepage">https://synfig.org</url>
  <url type="help">https://wiki.synfig.org/Category:Manual</url>
  <url type="bugtracker">https://github.com/synfig/synfig/issues</url>
  <url type="translate">https://explore.transifex.com/morevnaproject/synfig/</url>
  <url type="vcs-browser">https://github.com/synfig/synfig</url>
  <developer id="org.synfig">
    <name>Synfig</name>
  </developer>

  <supports>
    <control>pointing</control>
    <control>keyboard</control>
    <control>tablet</control>
    <display_length compare="le">3840</display_length>
  </supports>

  <recommends>
    <memory compare="ge">2048</memory> <!-- recommend at least 2GiB of memory -->
    <display_length compare="ge">1080</display_length>
  </recommends>

  <!-- never uses the internet, even if available -->
  <requires>
    <internet>offline-only</internet>
    <display_length compare="ge">768</display_length>
  </requires>

  <branding>
    <color type="primary" scheme_preference="light">#fafafa</color>
    <color type="primary" scheme_preference="dark">#023b5f</color>
  </branding>

  <translation type="gettext">synfigstudio</translation>
  <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
  <project_license>GPL-3.0</project_license>
  <content_rating type="oars-1.1" />
  <update_contact>konoplin_at_gmail.com</update_contact>
</component>
